<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="https://github.com/commoncriteria/transforms/raw/master/schemas/CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Crypto Catelog"
xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID006">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Crypto Catalog</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2017-04-19</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>Version 3.1R4</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>catelog; crypto</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date></date>
      <subject></subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2017-04-19</date>
      <subject>Initial Catalog</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">
    </section>
    <section id="glossary" title="Terms">The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
    technology terms used in this Extended Package. 
    <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms" id="ccterms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
          Evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Extended Package">EP</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category of
          products, which extends those in a Protection Profile.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category of
          products.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
          product.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>The product under evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A description of how a 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" /> satisfies the SFRs in a 
          <abbr linkend="ST" />.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A requirement to assure the security of the 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</description>
        </entry>
      </glossary>
    </subsection>
    <subsection id="techterms" title="Technology Terms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Secure Shell">SSH</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>Cryptographic network protocol for initiating text-based shell sessions on remote systems.
          </description>
        </entry>
		</glossary>
    </subsection>
	</section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">The Target of Evaluation
    (TOE) in this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> is a product which acts as an SSH client or server, or both. 
    <h:br/>This 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> describes the extended security functionality of SSH in terms of
    
    <cite linkend="bibCC" />. This EP can extend the Protection Profiles for <h:i>Application Software</h:i>,
      <h:i>General-Purpose Operating Systems</h:i>, <h:i>Mobile Device Management</h:i>, or <h:i>Virtualization</h:i>. It is
    expected that the content of this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> will be appropriately combined with the base PP to include selection-based
    requirements in accordance with the selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or
    objective components.
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibAppPP" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
    selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
    FCS_CKM.2.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.2.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
    FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibGPOS" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
    selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
    FCS_CKM.2.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.1.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
    FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibMDM" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
      selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
      FCS_CKM.1.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.1.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
      FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
      <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibVirt" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
      selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
      FIA_X509_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
      <h:br />
    An ST must identify the applicable version of the base PP and this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> in its conformance claims.</section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description>This 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> serves to extend the PP baselines with additional SFRs and associated
        Assurance Activities specific to SSH clients and servers. Assurance Activities are the
        actions that the evaluator performs in order to determine an SSH client or server's
        compliance to the SFRs.
          <h:br/>This 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> conforms to Common Criteria 
        <cite linkend="bibCC" /> for Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1,
        Revision 4. It is CC Part 2 extended and CC Part 3 conformant. In order to be conformant to
        this 
        <abbr linkend="EP" />, the 
        <abbr linkend="ST" /> must include all components in this 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> and the associated base PP that are: 
        <ul>
          <li>unconditional (which are always required)</li>
          <li>selection-based (which are required when certain selections are chosen in the
          unconditional requirements)</li>
        </ul>and may include optional and/or objective components that are desirable but not
        required for conformance. 
          <h:br/>In accordance with CC Part 1, dependencies are not included when they are addressed
        by other SFRs. The assurance activities provide adequate proof that any dependencies are
        also satisfied.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd">
  This Extended Package does not repeat the threats, assumptions, and organizational security
  policies identified in any base PPs, though they all apply given the conformance and hence
  dependence of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> on it. Together the threats, assumptions and organizational security
  policies of the base PP and those defined in this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> describe those addressed by the product as the Target of
  Evaluation.
  </chapter>
  
 
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
  to be fulfilled by the product. Those requirements comprise functional components from Part 2 of 
  <cite linkend="bibCC" />. The following notations are used: 
  <ul>
    <li>
    <b>Selection</b> (denoted by 
    <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options provided by the [CC] in stating
    a requirement.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by 
    <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): is used to assign a specific value to an unspecified parameter, such
    as the length of a password. Showing the value in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g. "(1)").</li>
  </ul>
  <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="sfr">The Security Functional Requirements
  included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
  Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
  components. 
  <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
    <f-component id="fcs_cop.1/UDE" name="Cryptographic Operation - User Data Encryption" status="threshold">
      <f-element id="fcs_cop.1.1(1)">
	      <title>The TSF shall perform user data encryption/decryption in accordance 
          with a specified cryptographic algorithm <selectables><selectable>cryptographic algorithm</selectable></selectables>
          and cryptographic key sizes <selectables><selectable>key sizes</selectable></selectables> that meet the following 
		      <selectables><selectable>list of standards</selectable></selectables>.
	  <h:br /><h:br />  
	  The following table provides the allowed choices for completion of the selection operations of FCS_COP.1/UDE: 
        </title>

	  <note role="application">There is app note here. What we really want is a nice table of the catalog options. And also, we would 
		  like the aactivity to be eactivity.
        </note>
        <aactivity>
	  <h:b>TSS</h:b>
        The evaluator shall check that the TSS includes a description of encryption function(s) used for user data encryption.
	The evaluator should check that this description of the selected encryption function includes the key sizes and modes
	of operation as specified in the table above per row.
	<h:br /><h:br />
	The evaluator shall check that the TSS describes the means by which the TOE satisfies constraints on algorithm
	parameters included in the selections made for <h:i>cryptographic algorithm</h:i> and <h:i>list of standards</h:i>.
          <h:br /> <h:br />
       	<h:b>KMDSD</h:b>
        The evaluator shall examine the KMDSD to ensure that the points at which user data encryption and decryption
	occurs are described, and that the complete data path for user data encryption is described. The evaluator checks
	that this description is consistent with the relevant parts of the TSS.
  	<h:br /> <h:br />
	If XTS-AES is used as the user data encryption algorithm then the evaluator shall check that the full length keys 
	are created by methods that ensure that the two halves are different and independent.
          <h:br />
          <h:br />
	<h:b>Guidance</h:b>
	If multiple encryption modes are supported, the evaluator examines the guidance documentation to determine that the 
	method of choosing a specific mode/key size by the end user is described. 
          <h:br />
          <h:br />
	<h:b>Tests</h:b>
	The following tests are conditional based upon the selections made in the SFR. The evaluator shall perform the 
	following test or witness respective tests executed by the developer if technically possible, otherwise an analysis 
	of the implementation representation has to be performed.
	Preconditions for testing:<h:br /><h:br />
	<h:list>
		<h:li>Specification of keys as input parameter to the function to be tested</h:li>
		<h:li>Specification of required input parameters such as modes</h:li>
		<h:li>Specification of user data (plaintext)</h:li>
		<h:li>Tapping of encrypted user data (ciphertext) directly in the non-volatile memory</h:li>
	</h:list><h:br /><h:br />
	<h:b>UDE1: AES-CBC Tests</h:b><h:br />
	For the AES-CBC tests described below, the plaintext, ciphertext, and IV values shall consist of 128-bit blocks. 
	To determine correctness, the evaluator shall compare the resulting values to those obtained by submitting the same 
	inputs to a known-good implementation.
 	<h:br />
        <h:br />
	These tests are intended to be equivalent to those described in NIST’s AES Algorithm Validation Suite (AESAVS) 
	(http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/aes/AESAVS.pdf). Known answer values tailored to exercise the 
	AES-CBC implementation can be obtained using NIST’s CAVS Algorithm Validation Tool or from NIST’s ACPV service for 
	automated algorithm tests (acvp.nist.gov), when available. It is not recommended that evaluators use values obtained 
	from static sources such as the example NIST’s AES Known Answer Test Values from the AESAVS document, or use values 
	not generated expressly to exercise the AES-CBC implementation.
 	<h:br />
        <h:br />
        <testlist>
		<test>
		<h:b>AES-CBC Known-Answer Tests (KAT)</h:b>
		<h:ul>KAT-1 (GFSBox):</h:ul><h:br />
             	To test the encrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall supply a set of five different plaintext 
		values for each selected key size and obtain the ciphertext value that results from AES-CBC encryption of 
		the given plaintext using a key value of all zeros and an IV of all zeros.<h:br /><h:br />
		To test the decrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall supply a set of five different ciphertext 
		values for each selected key size and obtain the plaintext value that results from AES-CBC decryption of the 
		given ciphertext using a key value of all zeros and an IV of all zeros.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
		<h:ul>KAT-2 (KeySBox):</h:ul><h:br />
             	To test the encrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall supply a set of five different key values 
		for each selected key size and obtain the ciphertext value that results from AES-CBC encryption of an all-zeros 
		plaintext using the given key value and an IV of all zeros.<h:br /><h:br />
		To test the decrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall supply a set of five different key values 
		for each selected key size and obtain the plaintext that results from AES-CBC decryption of an all-zeros 
		ciphertext using the given key and an IV of all zeros. 
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
		<h:ul>KAT-3 (Variable Key):</h:ul><h:br />
		To test the encrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall supply a set of keys for each selected key 
		size (as described below) and obtain the ciphertext value that results from AES encryption of an all-zeros plaintext 
		using each key and an IV of all zeros.<h:br /><h:br />
		Key <h:i>i</h:i> in each set shall have the leftmost <h:i>i</h:i> bits set to ones and the remaining bits to 
		zeros, for values of <h:i>i</h:i> 
		from 1 to the key size. The keys and corresponding ciphertext are listed in AESAVS, Appendix E.<h:br /><h:br />
		To test the decrypt functionality of AES-CBC, the evaluator shall use the same keys as above to decrypt the 
		ciphertext results from above. Each decryption should result in an all-zeros plaintext.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
		<h:ul>KAT-4 (Variable Text):</h:ul><h:br />
		To test the encrypt functionality of AES-CBC, for each selected key size, the evaluator shall supply a set of 
		128-bit plaintext values (as described below) and obtain the ciphertext values that result from AES-CBC 
		encryption of each plaintext value using a key of each size and IV consisting of all zeros.<h:br /><h:br />
		Plaintext value <h:i>i</h:i> shall have the leftmost <h:i>i</h:i> bits set to ones and the remaining bits set to zeros, for values 
		of <h:i>i</h:i> from 1 to 128. The plaintext values are listed in AESAVS, Appendix D.<h:br /><h:br />
		To test the decrypt functionality of AES-CBC, for each selected key size, use the plaintext values from above 
		as ciphertext input, and AES-CBC decrypt each ciphertext value using key of each size consisting of all zeros 
		and an IV of all zeros.
		</test>
            <test>
		    <h:b>AES-CBC Multi-Block Message Test</h:b>
              <h:br />
		    The evaluator shall test the encrypt functionality by encrypting nine <h:i>i</h:i>-block messages for each selected key 
		    size, for 2 ≤ <h:i>i</h:i> ≤ 10. For each test, the evaluator shall supply a key, an IV, and a plaintext message of length 
		    <h:i>i</h:i> blocks, and encrypt the message using AES-CBC. The resulting ciphertext values shall be compared to the results 
		of encrypting the plaintext messages using a known good implementation.<h:br /><h:br />
		The evaluator shall test the decrypt functionality by decrypting nine i-block messages for each selected key 
		    size, for 2 ≤ <h:i>i</h:i> ≤ 10. For each test, the evaluator shall supply a key, an IV, and a ciphertext message of 
		length <h:i>i</h:i> blocks, and decrypt the message using AES-CBC. The resulting plaintext values shall be compared to 
		the results of decrypting the ciphertext messages using a known good implementation.
            </test>
            <test>
              <h:b>AES-CBC Monte-Carlo Test (TBD)</h:b>
              <h:br />
              The evaluator shall test the encrypt functionality for each selected key size using 100 3-tuples of pseudo-random 
		values for plaintext, IVs, and keys. <h:br /><h:br />
		The evaluator shall supply a single 3-tuple of pseudo-random values for each selected key size. This 3-tuple of 
		plaintext, IV, and key is provided as input to the below algorithm to generate the remaining 99 3-tuples, and to 
		run each 3-tuple through 1000 iterations of AES-CBC encryption.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              	# Input: PT, IV, Key<h:br />
              	Key[0]=Key<h:br />
		IV[0]=IV<h:br />
		PT[0]=PT<h:br />
		for i = 1 to 100 {<h:br />
              		Output Key[i],IV[i],PT[0]<h:br />
		    	for j=1 to 1000 {<h:br />
		    		if j==1 {<h:br />
		    			CT[1] = AES-CBC-Encrypt(Key[i], IV[i],PT[1])<h:br />
              				PT[2] = IV[i]<h:br />
				} else {<h:br />
		    			CT[j] = AES-CBC-Encrypt(Key[i],PT[j])<h:br />
              				PT[j+1] = CT[j-1]<h:br />
		    		}<h:br />
		    	}<h:br />
		    	Output CT[1000]<h:br />
		    	If KeySize == 128 { Key[i+1] = Key[i] xor CT[1000] }<h:br />
  			If KeySize == 256 { Key[i+1] = Key[i] xor ((CT[999] leftshift 128) | CT[1000]) }<h:br />
  			IV[i+1] = CT[1000]<h:br />
  			PT[0] = CT[999]<h:br />
		} <h:br />
              <h:br /><h:br />
		The ciphertext computed in the 1000th iteration (CT[1000]) is the result for each of the 100 3-tuples for 
		each selected key size. This result shall be compared to the result of running 1000 iterations with the same 
		values using a known good implementation.
              <h:br /><h:br />
		The evaluator shall test the decrypt functionality using the same test as above, exchanging CT and PT, and 
		replacing AES-CBC-Encrypt with AES-CBC-Decrypt.
              <h:br /><h:br /> 
            </test>
	    <test>
		    <h:b>UDE2: AES-CCM Tests</h:b>
		These tests are intended to be equivalent to those described in the NIST document, “The CCM Validation System
		(CCMVS),” updated 9 Jan 2012, found at http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/mac/CCMVS.pdf.<h:br /><h:br />
		Known answer values tailored to exercise the AES-CCM implementation can be obtained using NIST’s CAVS 
		Algorithm Validation Tool or from NIST’s ACPV service for automated algorithm tests (acvp.nist.gov), when 
		available. It is not recommended that evaluators use values obtained from static sources such as 
		http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/mac/ccmtestvectors.zip or use values not generated expressly 
		to exercise the AES-CCM implementation.<h:br /><h:br />
		The evaluator shall test the generation-encryption and decryption-verification
		functionality of AES-CCM for the following input parameter and tag lengths:<h:br /><h:br />

		Keys: All supported and selected key sizes (e.g., 128, 192, 256 bits).<h:br /><h:br />
		Associated Data: Two or three values for associated data length: The minimum (≥ 0 bytes) and maximum (≤ 32 bytes) 
		    supported associated data lengths, and 2^16 (65536) bytes, if supported.<h:br /><h:br />
		Payload: Two values for payload length: The minimum (≥ 0 bytes) and maximum (≤ 32 bytes) supported payload 
		    lengths.<h:br /><h:br />
		Nonces: All supported nonce lengths (7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13).<h:br /><h:br />
		Tag: All supported tag lengths (4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16).<h:br /><h:br />

		The testing for CCM consists of five tests. To determine correctness in each of the below tests, the evaluator 
		shall compare the ciphertext with the result of encryption of the same inputs with a known good implementation.<h:br /><h:br />
		</test>
          </testlist>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </f-component>
    
  </subsection></section></chapter>
  
  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional">The baseline requirements (those that must
  be performed by the 
  <abbr linkend="TOE" />) are contained in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements specified in 
  <appref linkend="optional" />, 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />, and 
  <appref linkend="objective" />. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be
  included in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" />, but are not required in order for products to claim conformance to
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. The second type (in 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />) are requirements based on selections in the body of the 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
  appendix must be included. The third type (in 
  <appref linkend="objective" />) are components that are not required in order to conform to this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, but will be included in the baseline requirements in future versions of
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" /> author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated
  with those in 
  <appref linkend="optional" />, 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />, and 
  <appref linkend="objective" /> but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included
  in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" />.
  <h:br />None exists presently.
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based">As indicated in the introduction to
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the base PP or
  its underlying platform) are contained in the base PP and in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. There are additional requirements based on selections from the base PP
  and/or in the body of the 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements below will
  need to be included.</appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective">This Annex includes requirements that
  specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
  mandated in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available in
  commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" /> such that the product is still conformant to this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, and it is expected that they be included as soon as possible.
  <h:br/>None exists presently.</appendix>
  
  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - 
        <ul>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part 1:
            Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part 2:
            Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part 3:
            Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
        </ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibGPOS">
        <tag>GPOSPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=400">Protection Profile for General 
            Purpose Operating Systems
            </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibMDM">
        <tag>MDMPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=359">Protection Profile for Mobile 
            Device Management
          </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibAppPP">
        <tag>AppPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=394">Protection Profile for Application
            Software</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibVirt">
        <tag>VirtPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=408">Protection Profile for 
            Virtualization</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
 
  <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CBC</term>
        <description>Cipher Block Chaining</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECDSA</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>GCM</term>
        <description>Galois/Counter Mode</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IETF</term>
        <description>Internet Engineering Task Force</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IV</term>
        <description>Initialization Vector</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>MAC</term>
        <description>Message Authentication Code</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIST</term>
        <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PBKDF</term>
        <description>Password-Based Key Derivation Function</description>
      </entry>     
      <entry>
        <term>RFC</term>
        <description>Request for Comment (IETF)</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RSA</term>
        <description>Rivest Shamir Adelman</description>
      </entry>
    </acronyms>
  </appendix>
</PP>
