<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="https://github.com/commoncriteria/transforms/raw/master/schemas/CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Crypto Catelog"
xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID006">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Crypto Catalog</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2017-04-19</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>Version 3.1R4</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>catelog; crypto</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date></date>
      <subject></subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2017-04-19</date>
      <subject>Initial Catalog</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">
    </section>
    <section id="glossary" title="Terms">The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
    technology terms used in this Extended Package. 
    <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms" id="ccterms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
          Evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Extended Package">EP</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category of
          products, which extends those in a Protection Profile.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category of
          products.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
          product.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>The product under evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A description of how a 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" /> satisfies the SFRs in a 
          <abbr linkend="ST" />.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</description>
        </entry>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>A requirement to assure the security of the 
          <abbr linkend="TOE" />.</description>
        </entry>
      </glossary>
    </subsection>
    <subsection id="techterms" title="Technology Terms">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>
            <abbr title="Secure Shell">SSH</abbr>
          </term>
          <description>Cryptographic network protocol for initiating text-based shell sessions on remote systems.
          </description>
        </entry>
		</glossary>
    </subsection>
	</section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">The Target of Evaluation
    (TOE) in this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> is a product which acts as an SSH client or server, or both. 
    <h:br/>This 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> describes the extended security functionality of SSH in terms of
    
    <cite linkend="bibCC" />. This EP can extend the Protection Profiles for <h:i>Application Software</h:i>,
      <h:i>General-Purpose Operating Systems</h:i>, <h:i>Mobile Device Management</h:i>, or <h:i>Virtualization</h:i>. It is
    expected that the content of this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> will be appropriately combined with the base PP to include selection-based
    requirements in accordance with the selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or
    objective components.
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibAppPP" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
    selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
    FCS_CKM.2.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.2.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
    FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibGPOS" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
    selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
    FCS_CKM.2.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.1.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
    FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
    <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibMDM" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
      selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
      FCS_CKM.1.1, FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.1.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*,
      FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
      <h:br />
      This EP combined with the <cite linkend="bibVirt" /> must include selection-based requirements in accordance with the
      selections and/or assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include:
      FIA_X509_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.2.*.  
      <h:br />
    An ST must identify the applicable version of the base PP and this 
    <abbr linkend="EP" /> in its conformance claims.</section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description>This 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> serves to extend the PP baselines with additional SFRs and associated
        Assurance Activities specific to SSH clients and servers. Assurance Activities are the
        actions that the evaluator performs in order to determine an SSH client or server's
        compliance to the SFRs.
          <h:br/>This 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> conforms to Common Criteria 
        <cite linkend="bibCC" /> for Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1,
        Revision 4. It is CC Part 2 extended and CC Part 3 conformant. In order to be conformant to
        this 
        <abbr linkend="EP" />, the 
        <abbr linkend="ST" /> must include all components in this 
        <abbr linkend="EP" /> and the associated base PP that are: 
        <ul>
          <li>unconditional (which are always required)</li>
          <li>selection-based (which are required when certain selections are chosen in the
          unconditional requirements)</li>
        </ul>and may include optional and/or objective components that are desirable but not
        required for conformance. 
          <h:br/>In accordance with CC Part 1, dependencies are not included when they are addressed
        by other SFRs. The assurance activities provide adequate proof that any dependencies are
        also satisfied.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd">
  This Extended Package does not repeat the threats, assumptions, and organizational security
  policies identified in any base PPs, though they all apply given the conformance and hence
  dependence of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> on it. Together the threats, assumptions and organizational security
  policies of the base PP and those defined in this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> describe those addressed by the product as the Target of
  Evaluation.
  </chapter>
  
 
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
  to be fulfilled by the product. Those requirements comprise functional components from Part 2 of 
  <cite linkend="bibCC" />. The following notations are used: 
  <ul>
    <li>
    <b>Selection</b> (denoted by 
    <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options provided by the [CC] in stating
    a requirement.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by 
    <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): is used to assign a specific value to an unspecified parameter, such
    as the length of a password. Showing the value in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
    <li>
    <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g. "(1)").</li>
  </ul>
  <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="sfr">The Security Functional Requirements
  included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
  Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
  components. 
  <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
    <f-component id="fcs_cop.1/UDE" name="Cryptographic Operation - User Data Encryption" status="threshold">
      <f-element id="fcs_cop.1.1(1)">
	      <title>The TSF shall perform user data encryption/decryption in accordance 
          with a specified cryptographic algorithm <selectables><selectable>cryptographic algorithm</selectable></selectables>
          and cryptographic key sizes <selectables><selectable>cryptographic key sizes</selectable></selectables> that meet the following 
		      <selectables><selectable>list of standards</selectable></selectables>.
	  <h:br />
		      
	  The following table provides the allowed choices for completion of the selection operations of FCS_COP.1/UDE: 
        </title>

	  <note role="application">If the SSH software does provide its own crypto 
          the FCS claims will need to reflect that in the FCS selections from the base PP.
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          The evaluator shell review the TSF of the base PP to verify consistency with the functionality that
          was claimed by the base PP to ensure that applicable dependencies are met.
          <h:br />
         
          The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes the counter mechanism including 
          rationale that the counter values provided are unique. 
          <h:br />
          <h:br />
          AES-CTR Tests:
          <testlist>
            <test>
              Known Answer Tests (KATs)
              <h:br />
              There are four Known Answer Tests (KATs) described below.  For all KATs, the plaintext,
              IV, and ciphertext values shall be 128-bit blocks.  The results from each test may
              either be obtained by the validator directly or by supplying the inputs to the implementer
              and receiving the results in response.  To determine correctness, the evaluator shall
              compare the resulting values to those obtained by submitting the same inputs to a known
              good implementation.
              
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              To test the encrypt functionality, the evaluator shall supply a set of 10 plaintext 
              values and obtain the ciphertext value that results from encryption of the given plaintext
              using a key value of all zeros and an IV of all zeros.  Five plaintext values shall be encrypted
              with a 128-bit all zeros key, and the other five shall be encrypted with a 256-bit all zeros key. 
              To test the decrypt functionality, the evaluator shall perform the same 
              test as for encrypt, using 10 ciphertext values as input.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              To test the encrypt functionality, the evaluator shall supply a set of 10 key values
              and obtain the ciphertext value that results from encryption of an all zeros plaintext
              using the given key value and an IV of all zeros.  Five of the key values shall be 128-bit
              keys, and the other five shall be 256-bit keys. To test the decrypt functionality, the
              evaluator shall perform the same test as for encrypt, using an all zero ciphertext
              value as input.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              To test the encrypt functionality, the evaluator shall supply the two sets of key values
              described below and obtain the ciphertext values that result from AES encryption of an
              all zeros plaintext using the given key values an an IV of all zeros.  The first set of
              keys shall have 128 128-bit keys, and the second shall have 256 256-bit keys.  Key_i in
              each set shall have the leftmost i bits be ones and the rightmost N-i bits be zeros,
              for i in [1, N]. To test the decrypt functionality, the evaluator shall supply the two
              sets of key and ciphertext value pairs described below and obtain the plaintext value
              that results from decryption of the given ciphertext using the given key values and an
              IV of all zeros.  The first set of key/ciphertext pairs shall have 128 128-bit
              key/ciphertext pairs, and the second set of key/ciphertext pairs shall have 256 256-bit
              pairs. Key_i in each set shall have the leftmost i bits be ones and the rightmost N-i
              bits be zeros for i in [1, N].  The ciphertext value in each pair shall be the value 
              that results in an all zeros plaintext when decrypted with its corresponding key.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              To test the encrypt functionality, the evaluator shall supply the set of
              128 plaintext values described below and obtain the two ciphertext values that
              result from encryption of the given plaintext using a 128-bit key value of all
              zeros and using a 256 bit key value of all zeros, respectively, and an IV of all
              zeros. Plaintext value i in each set shall have the leftmost bits be ones and
              the rightmost 128-i bits be zeros, for i in [1, 128].  To test the decrypt functionality,
              the evaluator shall perform the same test as for encrypt, using ciphertext
              values of the same form as the plaintext in the encrypt test as input.
            </test>
            <test>
              Multi-Block Message Test
              <h:br />
              The evaluator shall test the encrypt functionality by encrypting an i-block 
              message where 1 less-than i less-than-or-equal to 10. For each i the evaluator 
              shall choose a key, IV, and plaintext message of length i blocks and encrypt
              the message, using the mode to be tested, with the chosen key. The ciphertext
              shall be compared to the result of encrypting the same plaintext message with
              the same key and IV using a known good implementation. The evaluator shall also 
              test the decrypt functionality by decrypting an i-block message where 1 less-than
              i less-than-or-equal to 10. For each i the evaluator shall choose a key and
              a ciphertext message of length i blocks and decrypt the message, using the mode 
              to be tested, with the chosen key. The plaintext shall be compared to the result
              of decrypting the same ciphertext message with the same key using a known good implementation.
            </test>
            <test>
              Monte-Carlo Test
              <h:br />
              For AES-CTR mode perform the Monte Carlo Test for ECB Mode on the encryption 
              engine of the counter mode implementation. There is no need to test the decryption engine.
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              The evaluator shall test the encrypt functionality using 200 plaintext/key pairs. 
              100 of these shall use 128 bit keys, and 100 of these shall use 256 bit keys.  
              The plaintext values shall be 128-bit blocks.  For each pair, 1000 iterations shall be run as follows:
              <h:br />
              <h:br />
              For AES-ECB mode<h:br />
              # Input: PT, Key<h:br />
              for i = 1 to 1000:<h:br />
              CT[i] = AES-ECB-Encrypt(Key, PT)<h:br />
              PT = CT[i]
              <h:br />
              The ciphertext computed in the 1000th iteration is the result for that 
              trial.  This result shall be compared to the result of running 1000 
              iterations with the same values using a known good implementation.  
            </test>
          </testlist>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
    </f-component>
    
  </subsection></section></chapter>
  
  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional">The baseline requirements (those that must
  be performed by the 
  <abbr linkend="TOE" />) are contained in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements specified in 
  <appref linkend="optional" />, 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />, and 
  <appref linkend="objective" />. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be
  included in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" />, but are not required in order for products to claim conformance to
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. The second type (in 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />) are requirements based on selections in the body of the 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
  appendix must be included. The third type (in 
  <appref linkend="objective" />) are components that are not required in order to conform to this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, but will be included in the baseline requirements in future versions of
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" /> author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated
  with those in 
  <appref linkend="optional" />, 
  <appref linkend="sel-based" />, and 
  <appref linkend="objective" /> but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included
  in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" />.
  <h:br />None exists presently.
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based">As indicated in the introduction to
  this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the base PP or
  its underlying platform) are contained in the base PP and in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />. There are additional requirements based on selections from the base PP
  and/or in the body of the 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements below will
  need to be included.</appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective">This Annex includes requirements that
  specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
  mandated in the body of this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" /> as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available in
  commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the 
  <abbr linkend="ST" /> such that the product is still conformant to this 
  <abbr linkend="EP" />, and it is expected that they be included as soon as possible.
  <h:br/>None exists presently.</appendix>
  
  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - 
        <ul>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part 1:
            Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part 2:
            Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
          <li>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part 3:
            Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4, September
          2012.</li>
        </ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibGPOS">
        <tag>GPOSPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=400">Protection Profile for General 
            Purpose Operating Systems
            </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibMDM">
        <tag>MDMPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=359">Protection Profile for Mobile 
            Device Management
          </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibAppPP">
        <tag>AppPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=394">Protection Profile for Application
            Software</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibVirt">
        <tag>VirtPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=408">Protection Profile for 
            Virtualization</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
 
  <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CBC</term>
        <description>Cipher Block Chaining</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECDSA</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>GCM</term>
        <description>Galois/Counter Mode</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IETF</term>
        <description>Internet Engineering Task Force</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IV</term>
        <description>Initialization Vector</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>MAC</term>
        <description>Message Authentication Code</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIST</term>
        <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PBKDF</term>
        <description>Password-Based Key Derivation Function</description>
      </entry>     
      <entry>
        <term>RFC</term>
        <description>Request for Comment (IETF)</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RSA</term>
        <description>Rivest Shamir Adelman</description>
      </entry>
    </acronyms>
  </appendix>
</PP>
